# Peter Harmazinski

Houston, TX

**Portfolio**: https://pharmazinski.pythonanywhere.com/ **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/peterharmazinski/

## **Summary**

Professional developer who specializes in analytics and data visualization. Passionate about user experience, mentoring, improving processes, and continuous learning. Recognized as a Lean Champion, Code for Good technical judge, and a Champion of JPMorgan Chase.

## **Technology**

• Tableau • SQL • Alteryx • Python • React • JavaScript

## **Experience**

## Tableau Lead Developer, Cigna/Evernorth

11/2020 - Current

- Partner with stakeholders, business analysts, and other developers to discover requirements, gather
  and transform data, design wireframes, and implement performant and responsive Tableau
  dashboards for audiences at all levels.
- Create standardized dashboards that are reusable by different teams who need the same data,
   resulting in less dashboards to maintain and reduced time to market.
- Design and implement data migration strategy to support firmwide initiative towards common curated data sources, resulting in other teams to take similar initiatives.
- Create and maintain a Tableau community chat to foster cross-team collaboration and knowledge sharing, resulting in 100+ members.
- Provide mentorship to internal and external team members on Tableau, analytics, design, technology, programming, and career development.

## Business Intelligence Developer, JPMorgan Chase

03/2018 - 11/2020

- Created Tableau and React dashboards to visualize metrics, simultaneously automating the process
  of collecting the data and improving the understandability of the information, resulting in 30,000+
  dashboard views per year.
- Implemented Alteryx and Node.js workflows and deploy to server to automate extraction, transformation, and loading of data from databases to Tableau Server and SharePoint.
- Formulated metrics to analyze testing data, which is reported monthly to managers and executives, thereby empowering management with more accurate information to make actionable decisions.

#### Web Developer, JPMorgan Chase

03/2017 - 03/2018

• Migrated the JPMorgan Markets container and admin applications from Oracle to Cassandra, thereby improving query speed by 75%.

• Created Splunk dashboards to visualize high- and low-level performance differences between Oracle and Cassandra, thereby ensuring a lens through which to identify issues and make improvements.

## Business Systems Analyst, JPMorgan Chase

08/2015 - 03/2017

- Designed and developed JavaScript dashboards to replace manual reporting, resulting in 270+ hours saved per year.
- Managed software release pilots by reviewing, triaging, and resolving issues with IT partners, conducting global conference calls with business managers, and multichannel communication.

## Fraud Analyst, JPMorgan Chase

03/2014 - 08/2015

• Led implementation of new reports by creating presentations, developing and conducting training, and analyzing data to look for trends, thereby receiving the award for Champion of Chase.

#### Online Technical Support Specialist, JPMorgan Chase

03/2013 - 03/2014

• Solved customers' problems efficiently by multitasking, thinking outside of the box, and asking appropriate questions to determine core issues, which resulted in a 99% customer satisfaction rate.

#### Russian Linguist Team Leader, United States Army

08/2003 - 08/2008

• Researched, gathered, organized, and reported data in a time-sensitive environment. As a result of working individually and as a member of a team, 100% of the strategic goals were achieved.

## **Education**

- Master's degree in Data Analytics (2020): Western Governors University
- Associate's degree in Computer Information Systems (2016): Florida Institute of Technology
- Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration (2011): University of the Incarnate Word

## **Certifications**

- SAS Statistical Business Analyst
- SAS Base Programming Specialist
- Alteryx Designer Core

## **Affiliations**

- Data Visualization Society
- Data Science Association
- Association for Computing Machinery

#### Service

- Viz for Social Good
- Code for Good
- Resolutions Hospice